asla.org 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy | asla.org

### Privacy Policy

_Effective Date: August 1, 2018_

Introduction  
The American Society of Landscape Architects (ASLA) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it at all times. This privacy statement explains how the ASLA collects, processes, and shares your personal information, your choices regarding the collection and use of such information, and the security measures ASLA employs to protect the information. By using ASLA web, mobile applications, and mobile sites, you agree to our practices concerning such information, which may be revised from time to time.

Each time you use our site, the current version of this policy will apply. Accordingly, whenever you use our site, you should check the date of this policy (which appears at the top) and review any changes since the last version. This policy is applicable to all site visitors, registered users, and all other users of our site.  
What Information We Collect and How we Use It

Data Collection - ASLA collects personal information from individuals while offering products and services, from affiliates, partners and other third parties. Prior to use of data from a third party, including public sources, ASLA will obtain your consent before contacting you if required by the law of the country in which you are located. ASLA also collects certain information from all visitors to our sites and from users of our mobile apps.

ASLA collects certain contact, demographic, and personal interest information about members, event attendees, and other registered users (in-person or online). Such information may include: name, telephone number, physical and email address, and other required and optional fields. In addition, credit card numbers may be collected by service providers who work on ASLA’s behalf to process your transactions.

ASLA also may collect and process:

  * Membership/Subscription information about your membership or subscription including your name, contact details such as address, phone number and email address (business or personal), age, job title, educational background, join date, and any other information related to your membership.
  * Payment and purchase information, including financial information such as credit/debit card and account numbers used to join or renew your membership or for any individual to purchase goods and services, including the ASLA Annual Meeting & Expo registration and online learning offerings.
  * Ethics investigations, relating to breaches of ASLA Code of Professional Ethics and ASLA Code of Environmental Ethics, in which complaints against members are adjudicated, with the result being possible suspension/expulsion from membership. This may include extensive information about a member's business or professional activities, including employment information, and similar information relating to other individuals involved in the investigation.

With regard to each of your visits to the website, ASLA will automatically collect the following information:

  * Technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer or device to the Internet, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform;
  * Information about your visit, including pages you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page, and any phone number used to call our customer service number; and
  * Location information

ASLA collects information that is sent automatically by your web browser and ASLA may use this information to generate aggregate statistics about visitors to its site, including, without limitation: IP addresses; browser type and plug-in details; device type (e.g., desktop, laptop, tablet, phone, etc.); operating system; and local time zone.

How we use information - ASLA may use your personal information for various purposes, including:

  * to carry out obligations arising from your membership, or any other contract entered into between us and to provide you with the information, events, products, and membership services that you request;
  * to provide _Landscape Architecture Magazine_ , LAND, and other publications, provided you have given your consent;
  * to improve content and communications and to respond to the interests and preferences of members, subscribers, other customers and potential customers;
  * to respond to questions and provide related membership services;
  * to provide information about other events, products and services that are similar to those that have already purchased, provided the individual has not opted-out of receiving that information;
  * if needed to process credit cards, with the assistance of a third-party processor, so that you may pay for membership, purchase products or services, or attend our events; and
  * to better understand the demographic makeup of the landscape architecture profession.

Tracking activity on our website - We use cookies to deliver our online services. We may also use information collected for data analytics purposes related to our site visitors and app users, for system maintenance, and to understand how visitors use our sites, apps, and services. We utilize third party analytics tools that use cookies or other tracking technologies to generate information on your use of our sites and apps (e.g., your IP address). This information may be transmitted to, and stored by, our third-party service providers. It is used to evaluate our visitor or app user statistics to improve content, navigation, and structure. We or our contractors may also transfer this information to third parties as required by law, or where such third parties process the information on our or our service provider's behalf.

With whom we may share information - The privacy of ASLA member information is governed by the [ASLA Member Information Confidentiality Policy](https://www.asla.org/ContentDetail.aspx?id=6354). This policy limits the types of personal data that is shared by ASLA and its chapters. Contact information is available to our members through our Membership Directory for use in networking with their peers. Members can set their profile to private if they do not want to appear in the directory. Landscape architecture firms, design/build firms, and multidisciplinary firms who employ ASLA members appear in FirmFinder. The firms may personalize the contact information provided in FirmFinder.

Disclosure to third parties - When disclosing personal information to third parties, ASLA obligates the recipient to use that information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the [ASLA Member Information Confidentiality Policy](https://www.asla.org/ContentDetail.aspx?id=6354). ASLA never sells your personal data or shares email addresses to third parties. ASLA may also share your information to fulfill legal obligations in connection with a lawsuit or similar proceeding; to respond to a matter of personal or public safety; to investigate security incidents; to protect our interests, rights, and property; and to effectuate a sale or transfer of assets or other business transaction. ASLA may also share personal information with regulatory authorities as may be required or requested under applicable law.

Use of third-party links - ASLA sites and apps may contain links to websites operated by third parties. ASLA does not control these websites or their content, and any information you provide to such sites is governed by the terms of that site's privacy policy. The inclusion of third party sites on ASLA sites or apps in no way constitutes an endorsement of the content, actions, or policies of the sites of others.

Data retention and storage - We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with our site. If you wish to cancel your membership/subscription or request that we no longer use your information to provide you service, contact us. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We maintain one or more databases to store your personal data and may keep such information indefinitely.

We will store your personal data, in a form which permits us to identify you, for no longer than is necessary for the purpose for which the personal data is processed. We may retain and use your personal data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements and rights, or if it is not technically reasonably feasible to remove it. Consistent with these requirements, we will try to delete your personal data quickly upon request.

Data security - ASLA is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust. ASLA takes steps to help protect personal information, however, no data transmission over the Internet or electronic storage of information is guaranteed to be secure.

How you can access and change your information  
You have some choices concerning ASLA use of your personal information. For example, if you have requested communications from ASLA, but do not wish to receive further information, you can "opt-out" by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link provided in the relevant communication. You may change your browser cookie settings, and you may request that ASLA:

  * Update, correct, or delete your personal information
  * Provide you with access to your personal information
  * Withdraw your consent to marketing or other communications
  * Change your preferences regarding our sharing of your personal information with third parties

If you are a member or registered user, you may make changes to your personal information by modifying your "My ASLA" account. If you are not a member or registered user, you may contact us as described below.

You may be located be in a country or region where data privacy or data protection laws differ from the United States. If you access our sites or apps, your personal information may be transferred to ASLA in other countries, including the United States.

You can exercise any of these rights by contacting us (see below for more information).

Changes to This Policy  
This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use or share your personal information, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice within the Services at least 30 days prior to the changes taking effect.

California Privacy Rights  
California residents have the right to annually request and obtain information free of charge about any third parties that received personal Information from the company during the preceding calendar year for direct marketing purposes by directing a request to the contact information provided below.

Do Not Track Signals  
Our websites do not respond to web browser "do not track" signals. ASLA and its service providers engage in information collection and disclosure practices, including tracking browsing history. We offer choices to all consumers, as described in this Privacy Statement regardless of the "do not track" choice made by the consumer. We may allow ad serving networks and other third parties to engage in online behavioral advertising and activities such as marketing automation.

European Privacy Rights  
Residents of the European Union have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You may have the right to request access to any personal data we hold about you as well as related information, including the purposes for processing the personal data, the recipients or categories of recipients with whom the personal data has been shared, where possible, the period for which the personal data will be stored, the source of the personal data, and the existence of any automated decision making. In addition, where you believe that ASAE has not complied with its obligations under this Notice or European law, you have the right to make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority, such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office.

We are headquartered in the United States. Your personal data may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, partners, merchants, or service providers who are located worldwide. If you are visiting our site from outside the United States, be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located, and our central database is operated. By using our service, you consent to any transfer of this information.

* * *

CONTACT US

American Society of Landscape Architects  
636 I (Eye) St., NW  
Washington, DC 20001-3735  
202-898-2444/888-999-ASLA
